<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./c74ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="crow.var" module="crow">

	<digest>
		Assign values to a variable on crow.
	</digest>

	<description>
		Specify a script variable to address as <o>crow.var</o>'s first argument.  Connect the output of <o>crow.var</o> to the input of the <o>crow</o> object.  Values sent to <o>crow.var</o> will be sent to the crow hardware module and stored in the specified variable.  
	</description>

	<!--METADATA-->
	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Sam Wolk + Dan Derks</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">crow</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">crow help</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Eurorack</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<!--ARGUMENTS-->
	<objarglist>
		<objarg name="variable" optional="1" type="symbol">
            <digest>
				Name of variable to address
			</digest>
			<description>
				Values sent to <o>crow.var</o>'s left inlet will be sent to crow and stored in this variable.
			</description>
        </objarg>
	</objarglist>

	<!--MESSAGES-->
	<methodlist>
		<method name="int">
            <arglist>
                <arg name="value" optional="0" type="int" />
            </arglist>
            <digest>
                Value to store
            </digest>
			<description>
				An integer sent to the left inlet will be stored in the specified variable.
			</description>
        </method>
		<method name="float">
            <arglist>
                <arg name="value" optional="0" type="float" />
            </arglist>
            <digest>
                Value to store
            </digest>
			<description>
				A float sent to the left inlet will be stored in the specified variable.
			</description>
        </method>
		<method name="symbol">
            <arglist>
                <arg name="value" optional="0" type="symbol" />
            </arglist>
            <digest>
                String or Lua chunk to store
            </digest>
			<description>
				A symbol sent to the left inlet will be stored in the specified variable.  If the symbol is wrapped in single quotes (i.e. <m>'foo'</m>, it will be treated as a string.  If it is not wrapped in quotes (i.e. <m>myVar</m> or <m>math.random(2)</m>), or wrapped in double quotes (i.e. <m>"lfo(2,3)"</m>), it will be treated as Lua code (i.e. a variable or a function call).  
			</description>
        </method>
		
		<method name="table">
            <digest>
                Set the variable to an empty table
            </digest>
			<description>
				The word <m>table</m>, when sent to <o>crow.var</o>'s first inlet, will overwrite <o>crow.var</o>'s specified variable with an empty table (i.e. <m>myVar = { }</m>).
			</description>
        </method>
		<method name="list">
            <digest>
                Convert a list to a table and store it.
            </digest>
			<description>
				A message with more than one element will be converted to a table where the first index in the table is the first element in the list, and so on.  Symbols are treated the same as when sending a single symbol: single-quotes for strings, no-quotes or double-quotes for Lua.
			</description>
        </method>
		<method name="index">
			<arglist>
                <arg name="index" optional="0" type="int" />
				<arg name="value" optional="0" type="symbol" />
            </arglist>
            <digest>
                Assign a value to an integer index in the table specified by <o>crow.var</o>'s variable.
            </digest>
			<description>
				The word <m>index</m> followed by an integer <m>index</m> and any <m>value</m>, when sent to <o>crow.var</o>'s first inlet, will write the value to the specified index in the table assigned to <o>crow.var</o>'s variable. 
				For instance, if <o>crow.var</o> is set to <m>myTable</m>, then <m>index 6 2.4</m> is equivalent to the Lua chunk <m>myTable[6] = 2.4</m>. 
				<br/><br/>NB: symbols are treated as variable names; symbols must be wrapped in single quotes to be treated as strings.
				</description>
        </method>
		<method name="keyval">
			<arglist>
                <arg name="key" optional="0" type="symbol" />
				<arg name="value" optional="0" type="symbol" />
            </arglist>
            <digest>
                Assign a value to a key in the table specified by <o>crow.var</o>'s variable.
            </digest>
			<description>
				The word <m>keyval</m> followed by a <m>key</m> and a <m>value</m>, when sent to <o>crow.var</o>'s first inlet, will write the value to the specified key in the table assigned to <o>crow.var</o>'s variable.
				For instance, if <o>crow.var</o> is set to <m>myTable</m>, then <m>keyval someKey 2.4</m> is equivalent to the Lua chunk <m>myTable.someKey = 2.4</m>. 
				 <br/><br/>NB: symbols are treated as variable names; symbols must be wrapped in single quotes to be treated as strings.
			</description>
        </method>
	</methodlist>

	<!--DISCUSSION-->
	<discussion>
	</discussion>

	<!--SEEALSO-->
	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name="crow"/>
		<seealso name="crow.volts"/>
		<seealso name="crow.function"/>
		<seealso name="crow.inputs"/>
		<seealso name="crow.adsr"/>
		<seealso name="crow.ar"/>
		<seealso name="crow.n2v"/>		
		<seealso name="crow.dyn"/>	
	</seealsolist>

	

</c74object>